<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Linux on Alberto Reineri</title>
		<link>https://albertoreineri.it/en/categories/linux/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Linux on Alberto Reineri</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://albertoreineri.it/en/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Web development on Linux</title>
			<link>https://albertoreineri.it/en/blog/web-development-on-linux/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://albertoreineri.it/en/blog/web-development-on-linux/</guid>
			<description>Development on Linux I have been developing software and websites for more than ten years now (with a break in between), and I have had the opportunity to use both Windows and Mac as well as Linux.
While I have primarily used Windows and Mac, during the last period where I worked closely with system administrators and did much more backend development than frontend, I felt the need to switch to something more performance-oriented for these activities.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="development-on-linux">Development on Linux</h1>
<p>I have been developing software and websites for more than ten years now (with a break in between), and I have had the opportunity to use both <a href="/blog/miglior-pc-per-sviluppatori-la-mia-esperienza/"><strong>Windows</strong></a> and <strong>Mac</strong> as well as <strong>Linux</strong>.</p>
<p>While I have primarily used <strong>Windows</strong> and <strong>Mac</strong>, during the last period where I worked closely with <strong>system administrators</strong> and did much more <strong>backend development</strong> than frontend, I felt the need to switch to something more <strong>performance-oriented</strong> for these activities.</p>
<h2 id="beginnings">Beginnings</h2>
<p>I started my career as a <strong>.NET developer.</strong> I used a PC with the marvelous <strong>Windows XP</strong>.</p>
<p>It truly was wonderful—<strong>stable</strong>, fast, capable of doing everything.</p>
<p>At that time, I used Visual Studio and developed <strong>management and CRM</strong> software for the <strong>Windows</strong> platform, so I was obliged to remain in the <strong>Microsoft</strong> environment.</p>
<p>Then I started developing some <strong>websites</strong>, always for the same company. Being proficient in .NET, we began developing with <strong>ASP</strong>, a language very similar to Visual Basic.</p>
<p>I remember that at the time, <strong>changing the operating system never even crossed my mind.</strong> Linux was still quite challenging, Mac was expensive, and neither allowed for developing software for Windows, so the matter ended there.</p>
<h2 id="my-first-mac">My first Mac</h2>
<p>With the first money I saved, I decided to buy my first Mac: a <strong>MacBook White</strong>.</p>
<p>I was fascinated by the Apple environment.</p>
<p>I made the purchase mainly to use it for <strong>recording music</strong>; I had no intention of using it for development.</p>
<p>I tried it at the beginning, but everything I was used to using didn&rsquo;t exist for Mac. Visual Studio wasn&rsquo;t available for Mac, and our sites ran on Windows servers, so there was nothing to be done.</p>
<p>I contented myself with the fantastic <strong>artistic department</strong> of the bitten apple. There was no comparison; drawing, video, and music software were decidedly on another level.</p>
<h2 id="a-period-of-pause">A period of pause</h2>
<p><strong>Then I stopped programming for a few years.</strong> I did something completely different; I graduated in a humanities subject and completely disconnected from computers.</p>
<p>I continued to use the <strong>Mac as a personal laptop</strong>, but I only used it for <strong>university</strong> and <strong>free time</strong>, and here I began to <strong>miss Windows</strong>.</p>
<p>The <strong>Office suite</strong>, the possibility of finding thousands of software for any type of problem, <strong>games</strong>, and much more were missing on the Mac&hellip;</p>
<p>So when the MacBook White finally died of old age (7 years of good service), <strong>I bought a Windows laptop.</strong></p>
<h2 id="return-to-windows">Return to Windows</h2>
<p>When I bought my current laptop, <strong>I was still studying</strong> and had not yet resumed my career as a developer, but <strong>I wanted to return to programming,</strong> to write some code, to develop something from scratch.</p>
<p>So I went to Unieuro and bought <strong>the laptop with the best value for money.</strong></p>
<h2 id="resuming-development">Resuming development</h2>
<p><strong>A year later, I started developing seriously again,</strong> and I felt great on <strong>Windows</strong>; after all, that&rsquo;s where I had started, and I felt at home.</p>
<p>Thanks to <strong>XAMPP</strong>, I could set up my own lamp stack in 5 minutes and start tinkering with <strong>WordPress</strong>, <strong>Laravel</strong>, and create my projects the way I prefer: using <strong>core PHP</strong>.</p>
<p>As I caught up with the times and learned to use the new tools, I increasingly realized that <strong>Windows was no longer the ideal choice for me.</strong></p>
<p>I was no longer creating management software but web applications, and <strong>the web runs on Linux.</strong></p>
<p>I started using <strong>Node.js</strong> and various <strong>JavaScript</strong> tools that work from the command line, and gradually, I began to discover how <strong>limiting PowerShell</strong> could be&hellip;</p>
<p>Then I expanded my skills as a backend developer, and here I had to make the leap to a <strong>more performant terminal</strong>, and that&rsquo;s when I discovered Linux.</p>
<p>I started using <strong>WSL</strong>, but it was all a bit <strong>too messy</strong> for my taste, so I switched to Linux proper.</p>
<h2 id="arrival-at-linux">Arrival at Linux</h2>
<p><strong>It wasn&rsquo;t love at first sight.</strong></p>
<p>I started installing Ubuntu as a virtual machine with <strong>VirtualBox</strong> to try to tinker a bit with the penguin.</p>
<p>The <strong>first impact</strong>, perhaps also due to a lifetime spent on other systems, was <strong>quite tragic</strong>&hellip;</p>
<p>Everything I wanted to do, I had to <strong>configure</strong>; there was very little that worked right away, and for a while, I abandoned the idea of Linux.</p>
<p>Then little by little, I <strong>reapproached it</strong>, trying to <strong>adapt my way of thinking to this system</strong>, and everything changed.</p>
<p>The trick is to <strong>stop wanting Linux to resemble Windows or Mac OS,</strong> but to try to understand what it really is; then you can appreciate its infinite qualities.</p>
<p>Installing libraries, managing components, using command-line software, <strong>everything is much easier on Linux</strong>, everything works on the first try.</p>
<p>Configuring Vagrant correctly on Windows took much more time than on Ubuntu, and so much more.</p>
<p>Most of the time, all you need to do is <strong>run a command from the terminal, and voilà</strong>, everything works perfectly.</p>
<p>As a developer from now on, I think I will only use Linux distros, leaving a partition with Windows in case I have to do specific work with Photoshop (currently happily replaced with Pixlr) or other software available only for Windows.</p>
<p>In addition to being better from a developer&rsquo;s perspective, there is also the whole issue of <strong>open source</strong> behind it, the largest community project in history, the <strong>opposition to multinational corporations</strong>, the <strong>fight against planned obsolescence of laptops</strong>, and much more, but this is not the time to address these issues.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>As a developer, I would suggest that anyone <strong>switch to Linux</strong> (except those developing for iOS or specifically for Windows). Certainly, <strong>the beginning is not easy</strong>; you need to tinker a bit, bump your head a few times, but once you get into the right <strong>mood</strong>, everything flows smoothly and quickly.</p>
<p>For now, I&rsquo;m getting along very well with <strong><a href="https://www.ubuntu-it.org/">Ubuntu</a></strong> because I like <strong>Gnome</strong>. I tried other distros, but in the end, there isn&rsquo;t much difference; everything can be installed on any distro. So I went for Ubuntu for its <strong>stability</strong>.</p>
<p>I have been using it as a <strong>primary system for a couple of months</strong> now, and I think it will remain so for a long time. This way, I can <strong>finally free myself from Apple&rsquo;s pressing marketing</strong>, which, to be honest, is a constant temptation but would end up making me a slave to the apple&hellip; You know that if you buy a Mac, you want an iPhone, then an iPad, and an Apple Watch, and in the end, you always use the same three apps&hellip;</p>
<p>Even <strong>Windows laptops</strong> are becoming increasingly <strong>beautiful</strong> and tempting, with hardware that seems to age faster and faster. Of course, if you put an i7 in an ultrabook without a cooling system, you either melt the PC or castrate it and turn it into an i3. In the end, it&rsquo;s all marketing&hellip;</p>
<p>With <strong>Linux</strong>, on the other hand, you can take an <strong>i5</strong> from any generation, throw in an **SSD</p>
<p>** and <strong>8GB</strong> of RAM, and you&rsquo;re good for years without performance issues and more.</p>
<p>Of course, there&rsquo;s the problem of <strong>battery life</strong>, which is not as well optimized on Linux&hellip; But in the end, I use <strong>Linux for work</strong>, connected to the power, and when I want to chill on the couch, I can use Windows and enjoy a few more hours away from the cables.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
