<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Tech on Alberto Reineri</title>
		<link>https://albertoreineri.it/en/categories/tech/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Tech on Alberto Reineri</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 09:34:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://albertoreineri.it/en/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Usare il browser senza mouse – Hacker Style</title>
			<link>https://albertoreineri.it/en/blog/usare-il-browser-senza-mouse-hacker-style/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 09:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://albertoreineri.it/en/blog/usare-il-browser-senza-mouse-hacker-style/</guid>
			<description>Passiamo molto, moltissimo tempo sul browser ormai, e usare il mouse per la navigazione può essere frustranete per noi sviluppatori… Ma è possibile farne a meno e muoversi solamente utilizzando la tastiera, come un vero hacker! Vediamo come si fa.
Vimium Extension Per prima cosa devi scaricare l&amp;rsquo;estensione Vimium. Io uso Google Chrome, ma è presente anche per Firefox e Safari (se usi Brave o Edge non preoccuparti, puoi installare l&amp;rsquo;estensione per Google Chrome, funzionerà perfettamente perché questi browser condividono la stessa base).</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Passiamo molto, moltissimo tempo sul browser ormai, e usare il mouse per la navigazione può essere frustranete per noi sviluppatori… Ma è possibile farne a meno e muoversi solamente utilizzando la tastiera, come un vero hacker! Vediamo come si fa.</p>
<h2 id="vimium-extension">Vimium Extension</h2>
<p>Per prima cosa devi scaricare l&rsquo;estensione <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/vimium/dbepggeogbaibhgnhhndojpepiihcmeb" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Vimium</a>. Io uso Google Chrome, ma è presente anche per <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/it/firefox/addon/vimium-ff/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Firefox</a> e <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/vimari/id1480933944?mt=12" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Safari</a> (se usi Brave o Edge non preoccuparti, puoi installare l&rsquo;estensione per Google Chrome, funzionerà perfettamente perché questi browser condividono la stessa base).</p>
<p>Dopo averla installata potrete iniziare ad utilizzare il vostro browser direttamente dalla tasitera.</p>
<p>La base dei comandi è quella del software Vim, quindi se siete su Linux probabilmente vi troverete già a vostro agio, altrimenti non preoccupatevi, basterà qualche minuti di pratica per abbandonare il mouse per sempre!</p>
<p>Ecco i comandi principali per utilizzarlo:</p>
<h2 id="navigare-nella-pagina-corrente">Navigare nella pagina corrente:</h2>
<pre class="wp-block-code"><code>?       mostra l'elenco dei comandi disponibili (molto utile all'inizio)
h       scroll verso sinistra
j       scroll verso il basso
k       scroll verso l'alto
l       scroll verso destra
gg      scroll in cima alla pagina
G       scroll in fondo alla pagina
d       scroll in basso di metà pagina
u       scroll in alto di metà pagina
f       apri un link nella tab corrente
F       apri link in nuova tab
r       ricarica
gs      visualizza codice sorgente</code></pre>
<h2 id="navigare-in-altre-pagina">Navigare in altre pagina:</h2>
<pre class="wp-block-code"><code>o       Apri URL
O       Apri URL in nuova tab
b       Apri preferiti
B       Apri preferiti in nuova tab</code></pre>
<h2 id="cronologia">Cronologia:</h2>
<pre class="wp-block-code"><code>H       Vai a pagina precedente
L       Vai a pagina successiva</code></pre>
<h2 id="manipolazione-tabs">Manipolazione tabs:</h2>
<pre class="wp-block-code"><code>J, gT      Vai un tab verso sinistra
K, gt      Vai un tab verso destra
g0         Vai alla prima tab
g$         Vai all'ultima tab
t          Crea tab
x          Chiudi tab corrente
X          Riapri tab chiusa
T          Cerca fra le tab</code></pre>
<p>Ecco qua, questi sono solamente i comandi principali, ne esistono altri che puoi leggere qua: <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/vimium/dbepggeogbaibhgnhhndojpepiihcmeb" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/vimium/dbepggeogbaibhgnhhndojpepiihcmeb">https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/vimium/dbepggeogbaibhgnhhndojpepiihcmeb</a></a></p>
<p>E questo è tutto! Non ti resta che provare ad utilizzarli e vedrai che in breve tempo potrai usare il browser totalmente in hacker style ?‍?</p>
<p>Come sempre <em>buon codice!</em></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>I love Linux, but I&#39;m still on Mac...</title>
			<link>https://albertoreineri.it/en/blog/i-love-linux-but-im-still-on-mac.../</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 22:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://albertoreineri.it/en/blog/i-love-linux-but-im-still-on-mac.../</guid>
			<description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following me for a while, you probably know how much I love the Linux world! It&amp;rsquo;s an environment that sometimes gives me a headache, makes me angry, forces me to dig into things to understand how they work, but it also has the beauty of making us feel more in control of our PCs, understand how they work under the hood, and manage them better to our liking!</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;ve been following me for a while, you probably know how much I love the <a href="/blog/perche-dovremmo-tutti-passare-a-linux-e-perche-non-lo-facciamo/">Linux</a> world! It&rsquo;s an environment that sometimes gives me a headache, makes me angry, forces me to dig into things to understand how they work, but it also has the beauty of making us feel more in control of our PCs, understand how they work under the hood, and manage them better to our liking!</p>
<p>Oh, before someone starts insulting me, in this article, I&rsquo;m talking about Linux Desktop! I&rsquo;ve been using Linux exclusively on my servers for years, and everything runs smoothly there! (Even on the server, though, it&rsquo;s not all that automatic; you need to study to understand the basics, but once everything is set up, it works great!)</p>
<p>Well, with the necessary explanations made, let&rsquo;s get to the point!</p>
<h2 id="im-still-on-mac-os8230">I&rsquo;m still on Mac OS…</h2>
<p>If you&rsquo;ve watched my recent videos, you&rsquo;ve surely noticed that I&rsquo;ve filmed everything on <a href="/blog/nuovo-macbook-pro-2020-per-sviluppo-web/">Mac OS</a>. Well, yes, after repeatedly stating my love for Linux, here I am still using my MacBook Pro… What kind of inconsistent person am I…..</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not afraid to admit it; I often tell myself, I&rsquo;m inconsistent, and I don&rsquo;t like it at all… But unfortunately, it&rsquo;s not that simple.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve tried several times to switch permanently to Linux, but I&rsquo;ve always had to backtrack, and now I think I&rsquo;ve found the definitive reason, but as a good storyteller, I&rsquo;ll only reveal it at the end of this article. (Of course, if you&rsquo;re really impatient, you can quickly scroll to the conclusion…)</p>
<h2 id="why-i-love-linux">Why I love Linux</h2>
<p>There are many reasons why I love the Linux world, but the thing I prefer is that it disconnects from every marketing mechanism that constantly afflicts us today. We don&rsquo;t have time to buy something before it&rsquo;s already replaced by a more performant model. And finally, products have a predetermined lifespan; planned obsolescence is now a given!</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t like this at all…. I don&rsquo;t want to waste time watching fantastic product presentations that make me want to waste my money on often unnecessary equipment…</p>
<p>Moreover, Linux is meritocratic! The more you know, the less you struggle, that&rsquo;s it. If you&rsquo;re a beginner, you hate it with all your heart, then when you start tinkering with it properly, you can&rsquo;t do without it! You&rsquo;re the master of your machine, and you can use it exactly as you want!</p>
<p>Finally, in a world where our privacy no longer has much value, our metadata are in plain sight, and cybersecurity is becoming increasingly important, open source can guarantee a good level of protection! I&rsquo;m not a privacy fanatic; I also have a Gmail account, but I believe you need to have the right awareness, try to strike a balance between accessing any content with our personal data and encrypting every single file on the PC… No paranoia, but not too much laxity either.</p>
<h2 id="why-i-havent-fully-switched-to-linux-yet">Why I haven&rsquo;t fully switched to Linux yet</h2>
<p>As I mentioned at the beginning, I&rsquo;m still on Mac, even if I&rsquo;m not fully satisfied… And all this is because of the hardware I have available, at least that&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;m telling myself right now.</p>
<p>Some time ago, I saw a very interesting video from one of my favorite creators: Riccardo Palombo. In a YouTube video, he said, &ldquo;We don&rsquo;t need new hardware, but new software,&rdquo; or something very similar. What a wonderful title! But unfortunately, it doesn&rsquo;t work for me….</p>
<p>Hold on a moment, Riccardo is right, and I agree with him on the software issue, but I&rsquo;ve noticed that, at least for me, hardware is also very, very important!</p>
<p>If I&rsquo;m writing from my MacBook Pro, it&rsquo;s certainly not for Mac OS, nor for the software inside. I don&rsquo;t even care much about Photoshop lately, but it&rsquo;s for the hardware!</p>
<p>The keyboard, touchpad, screen, battery, microphone, fans, and charging times are good on my Mac, and I&rsquo;m still talking about the Intel version. There&rsquo;s nothing exceptional, but everything works great; I&rsquo;ve never had crashes, and it&rsquo;s a well-balanced computer and, all in all, quiet (except when I work with Docker…)</p>
<p>Besides the Mac, I have an ASUS notebook where I use Linux, and I&rsquo;ve come to the conclusion that the weakest point of the PC is precisely the hardware… In particular, I have a dreadful screen, very noisy fans, and a ridiculous battery…</p>
<p>Certainly, it&rsquo;s not the right notebook to use with Linux, but when I bought it, I didn&rsquo;t think I would become penguin-dependent ? ?.</p>
<p>With the Mac, on the other hand, I can work peacefully without fear of running out of battery without realizing it, being able to record my podcast directly from the laptop&rsquo;s microphone without attaching anything external (also because it doesn&rsquo;t have many ports ?), and I can go through the day with my eyes still healthy and not tearing up like when I use the ASUS….</p>
<p>The only way I work well with the ASUS is by using it as if it were a desktop PC. I attach an external keyboard, mouse, and screen, close it, and forget I have a notebook, then I have to say it works very well.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, though, for my lifestyle, it&rsquo;s essential to have a laptop I can trust. I often move for a few days to the mountains where I don&rsquo;t have much space, and for the moment, the Mac is really convenient!</p>
<p>Advantages: with a single charger, I can charge the Mac, Smartphone, and iPad (with a USB-C to Lightning connector), I can use the iPad as a second screen without connecting any cables, and I can do without the mouse because the touchpad is fantastic!</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>And voilà, that&rsquo;s it! So now I&rsquo;m still trapped in the Apple world. For heaven&rsquo;s sake, if I put aside ideological concepts, I could stay like this for life, but the pumping marketing, overpricing, and the &ldquo;fashion&rdquo; factor don&rsquo;t make me feel entirely comfortable…</p>
<p>How can I solve it? I should try to get my hands on a nice ThinkPad or XPS and see how I feel, but at the moment, I don&rsquo;t have the budget available to do this test…</p>
<p>It should also be said that choosing a laptop for Linux is not that easy…. Companies specializing in Linux notebooks are emerging, such as the Spanish Slimbook, but I need to study their products better before making a purchase.</p>
<p>In the end, all I need is a notebook with 4 quality components: keyboard, touchpad, battery, and screen. Unfortunately, it often happens that Windows laptops focus a lot on the processor and RAM and less on the user experience, which, for us programmers, is very important, at least for me.</p>
<p>If I have to spend ten hours a day on the PC, it must at least be nice and pleasant to use!</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s all for now; as soon as I get my hands on a ThinkPad, I&rsquo;ll let you know more!</p>
<p>Keep Coding ?</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Windows VS Mac for Web Development: My Experience</title>
			<link>https://albertoreineri.it/en/blog/windows-vs-mac-for-web-development-my-experience/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 21:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://albertoreineri.it/en/blog/windows-vs-mac-for-web-development-my-experience/</guid>
			<description>Today, I want to share my experience using these two operating systems, the eternal battle between Windows and Mac. I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss it from both a developer&amp;rsquo;s and an average user&amp;rsquo;s perspective since I use the computer for work and leisure, for programming, answering emails, writing documents, scheduling appointments, and more.
During my ten years of programming, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to use both Windows and Mac, each for several years. I&amp;rsquo;ve reached my conclusion, which is somewhat contrary to the usual discussions on various forums and social media in the industry.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I want to share <strong>my experience</strong> using these two operating systems, the eternal battle between Windows and Mac. I&rsquo;ll discuss it from both a developer&rsquo;s and an average user&rsquo;s perspective since I use the computer for work and leisure, for programming, answering emails, writing documents, scheduling appointments, and more.</p>
<p>During my ten years of programming, I&rsquo;ve had the opportunity to use <strong>both Windows and Mac</strong>, each for several years. I&rsquo;ve reached <strong>my conclusion</strong>, which is somewhat contrary to the usual discussions on various forums and social media in the industry.</p>
<h2 id="my-early-years">MY EARLY YEARS</h2>
<p>I <strong>started</strong> my career as a <strong>vb.net programmer</strong>, so I was using a <strong>Windows</strong> PC by necessity. It was a somewhat worn-out desktop running Windows <strong>XP</strong>. I must say, <strong>I didn&rsquo;t find it bad at all</strong>. Developing management software, the clients in 99.9% of cases had a Windows PC (there were very few Apple products around at that time, at least in my area), and thus the program had to run on that operating system. Those first four years of programming made me appreciate the operating system of good old Bill Gates. I got to <strong>know practically all keyboard shortcuts</strong> and customization options available. I could be very fast with my PC, and <strong>I knew my work environment perfectly</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="macbook-white">MACBOOK WHITE</h2>
<p>Then, more out of curiosity, I <strong>bought</strong> a Mac, specifically the <strong>Macbook White</strong>. Beautiful! <strong>Aesthetically, it had no comparison</strong> with the competition. A completely white PC, without designs, patterns, without anything superfluous.</p>
<p><strong>That&rsquo;s when my journey into the Apple world began</strong>. And it went well.</p>
<p>From a design perspective, Mac easily won, plus it had a program I loved and used a lot: Garageband! The simplicity of that software was terrific! I could record decently even without an audio interface, without any lag, and the default effects were fantastic! Unfortunately, I never found anything like it on Windows&hellip;</p>
<p>But there was always <strong>something that didn&rsquo;t sit right with me&hellip;</strong></p>
<p>It was beautiful, the battery seemed infinite, it was smooth and fast, but <strong>too closed!</strong> Perhaps it&rsquo;s predictable, but being a closed system didn&rsquo;t appeal to me at all!</p>
<p><strong>I&rsquo;ve always been a tinkerer.</strong> As soon as I get my hands on any machine, I have to understand how it works, how to make it work better, and how to play around with it. And with the Mac, I couldn&rsquo;t do much&hellip;</p>
<h2 id="issues">ISSUES</h2>
<p>And here we come to the heart of the Windows VS Mac battle.</p>
<p>The first problem was the <strong>Office suite</strong>. At that time, the only alternative was OpenOffice, but compatibility was not 100%. Sometimes, opening a Word file would result in completely messed-up formatting&hellip; and that bothered me a lot. Of course, I could have bought Office for Mac, but I didn&rsquo;t want to&hellip; (OK? :))</p>
<p>Then, on the <strong>programming</strong> side, I felt a bit stuck. While Visual Basic is a very basic language, it was the one I knew at the time, and I couldn&rsquo;t do anything with my Mac. I had installed Windows on a virtual machine, but it was very slow, and I couldn&rsquo;t work properly&hellip;</p>
<p>Even web development wasn&rsquo;t that straightforward for me! I used <strong>XAMPP</strong>, and at that time, I remember there was no XAMPP for Mac. So, I had downloaded MAMP, but I didn&rsquo;t like it much&hellip;</p>
<p>Finally, <strong>I couldn&rsquo;t play games</strong>&hellip; and even though I was never a hardcore gamer, occasionally launching a simple game to relax wasn&rsquo;t bad.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s say I felt restricted. If with Windows, I could do whatever I wanted, install anything, modify, experiment until I had to format the computer because of all the mess I had created, with the Mac, I could do almost nothing&hellip; Sure, I avoided creating messes, but I liked it!</p>
<h2 id="back-to-windows">BACK TO WINDOWS</h2>
<p>After 6 years, I had to change the PC; <strong>the little Macbook White couldn&rsquo;t take it anymore</strong>, and I returned to Windows.</p>
<p>That time in the Windows Vs Mac battle, Windows won.</p>
<p>Today, <strong>Mac prices are truly prohibitive</strong>&hellip; My Macbook White started at a price of €1000, and I remember getting it on sale at Euronics for €800. Those were still acceptable figures for a PC with 500GB HDD and 4GB RAM at that time.</p>
<p>Now, if you want a base model, you have to spend <strong>almost twice as much</strong>, for just 128GB of storage, a truly ridiculous amount, and without having USB, SD, and HDMI ports, which I still find fundamentally important.</p>
<p><strong>So, I went back to Windows, and I must say I&rsquo;m thrilled!</strong></p>
<p><strong>I can truly do everything!</strong> I immediately started tinkering again, and after two weeks, I had to format the PC because I had installed a bunch of nonsense, but I was happy! That&rsquo;s how I like to live with my PC; I want to be the one deciding how to make it work!</p>
<p>Now I can <strong>program</strong>, <strong>record</strong> music, <strong>play games</strong>, <strong>write</strong>, <strong>edit</strong> videos, use <strong>virtual machines</strong>, etc., without any slowdowns. Spending less than on a Macbook, I got a Core i7 with 16GB of RAM, 128GB SSD, 1TB HDD, and a 4GB graphics card! Basically, a powerhouse, for less than €100</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
